const quizDB = [
    {
        question: "Q1: What is the full form of HTML?",
        a:"HighText Machine Language",
        b:"HyperText and links Markup Language",
        c:"HyperText Markup Language",
        d:"None of these",
        ans:"ans3"
    },
    {
        question: "Q2: Which of the following HTML attribute is used to define inline styles?",
          
        a:"style",
        b:"type",
        c:"class",
        d: "None of the above",
        ans:"ans1"

    },
   {
        question: "Q3: What are the types of unordered or bulleted list in HTML?",
          
    a:"disc, square, triangle",
    b:"polygon, triangle, circle",
    c:" disc, circle, square",
    d: "All of the above",
    ans:"ans3"
   },
   {
    question: "Q4: What are the types of unordered or bulleted list in HTML?",

    a: "disc, square, triangle",
    b: "polygon, triangle, circle",
    c: " disc, circle, square",
    d: "All of the above",
    ans: "ans3"
},
{
   question: "Q5: CSS stands for?",

    a: "Cascade style sheets",
    b: "Color and style sheets",
    c: "Cascading style sheets",
    d: "None of the above",
    ans: "ans3"
},
{
   question: "Q6: Which of the following is the correct syntax for referring the external style sheet?",

    a:"<style src = example.css>",
    b: "<style src = example.css>",
    c: "<stylesheet> example.css </stylesheet>",
    d: "<link rel=stylesheet type=text/css href=example.css>",
    ans: "ans4"
},
{
    question: "Q7: Which of the following CSS property is used to set the background image of an element?",

    a: "background-attachment",
    b: "background-image",
    c: "background-color",
    d: "None of the above",
    ans: "ans2"
},
{
    question: "Q8:  Which one of the following also known as Conditional Expression?",

    a: "Alternative to if-else",
    b: "Switch statement",
    c: "If-then-else statement",
    d: "immediate if",
    ans: "ans4"
},

{
    question: "Q9:In JavaScript, what is a block of statement?",

    a: "Conditional block",
    b: "block that combines a number of statements into a single compound statement",
    c: "both conditional block and a single statement",
    d: "block that contains a single statement",
    ans: "ans2"

},
{
    question: "Q10: The function and  var are known as:",

    a: "Keywords",
    b: "Data types",
    c: "Declaration statements",
    d: "Prototypes",
    ans: "ans3"
},
{
    question: "Q11:  Which of the following variables takes precedence over the others if the names are the same?",

    a: "Global variable",
    b: "The local element",
    c: "The two of the above",
    d: "None of the above",
    ans: "ans2"
},
{
    question: "Q12: Which of the following type of a variable is volatile?",

    a: "Mutable variable",
    b: "Dynamic variable",
    c: "Volatile variable",
    d: "Immutable variable",
    ans: "ans1"
},
{
    question: "Q13: Which of the following option is used as hexadecimal literal beginning?",

    a: "00",
    b: "0x",
    c: "0X",
    d: "Both 0x and 0X",
    ans: "ans4",
},
    {
    question:"Q14:  In JavaScript the x===y statement implies that:",

    a: "Both x and y are equal in value, type and reference address as well",
    b: "Both are x and y are equal in value only",
    c: "Both are equal in the value and data type",
    d: "Both are not same at all",
    ans: "ans3",
    },
    {
        question: "Q15: In JavaScript, what will be used for calling the function definition expression:",

    a: "Function prototype",
    b: "Function literal",
    c: "Function calling",
    d: "Function declaration",
    }
];

const question= document.querySelector('.question');
const option1= document.querySelector('.#option1');
const option2= document.querySelector('.#option2');
const option3= document.querySelector('.#option3');
const submit= document.querySelector('.#submit');

const answers = document.querySelectorAll('.answer');
const showScore = document.querySelector('#showScore');

let questionCount = 0;
let score = 0;

const loadQuestion = () => {
    const questionList = quizDB[questionCount];
    question.innerText = questionList.question;

    option1.innerText= questionList.questionList.c;
    option2.innerText= questionList.questionList.a;
    option3.innerText= questionList.questionList.c;
}

loadQuestion();

const getCheckedAnswer = () => {
let answer;

answers.forEach((curAnsElem) => {
    if(curAnsElem.checked){
        answer = curAnsElem.id;
    }
});
return answer;
};

const deselectAll = () => {
    answers.forEach((curAnsElem)=> curAnsElem.checked=false);
}
submit.addEventListerner('click', () => {
    const checkedAnswer = getCheckedAnswer();
    console.log(checkedAnswer);

    if(checkedAnswer == quizDB[questionCount].ans){
    score++;
};

questionCount++;

deselectAll();

if(questionCount < quizDB.length){
    loadQuestion();
} else{
    showScore.innerHTML= `
    <h3> You Scored ${score}/$ {quizDB.length} </h3>
    <button class="btn" onclick="location.reload()"> Play Again </button>
    `;

    showScore.classList.remove('scoreArea');
}
});